**
- ORDER UP!
- 订购！
- HERE.
[clank]
- 这里。
[铮铮]
- GOO!
- 粘性物！
- HEY, THERE.
- 嘿。
- [raspberry]
- [覆盆子]
NUM, NUM!
数，数！
- AW, DOES BABY
WANT A KRABBY PATTY, HMM?
- 哇，宝贝吗？
想要一份蟹肉饼，嗯？
- AW.
- AW。
- BABY'S FIRST KRABBY PATTY.
[sniffles]
- 宝宝的第一个蟹肉饼。
[抽鼻子]
- THAT DIABOLICAL FIEND!
- 那个恶魔！
- I CAN'T BELIEVE
THIS IS WORKING!
- 我不敢相信
这是有效的！
IT'S LIKE TAKING CANDY
FROM A BABY--
就像吃糖果一样
从婴儿开始——
WITH A BABY.
带着婴儿。
- STOP RIGHT THERE,
YOU THIEVIN' INFANT!
- 就停在那里，
你这个小偷婴儿！
[mechanical ratcheting]
[机械棘轮]
[growls]
[咆哮]
- YI-EEH! THAT'S HARSH.
- 哎呀！这太严酷了。
- SO YOU THOUGHT YOU COULD
PULL A FAST ONE, EH?
- 所以你认为你可以
拉一个快的，呃？
NOW, COME OUT OF THERE,
YOU LITTLE PEST!
现在，从那里出来，
你这个小害虫！
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- [gasps]
WHAT'S HE DOING?
- [喘气]
他在做什么？
YOU LEAVE
THAT POOR BABY ALONE!
你离开
那个可怜的孩子独自一人！
- OKAY.
- 好的。
I GUESS WE'RE GONNA HAVE
TO DO THIS THE HARD WAY.
我想我们将会有
要以困难的方式做到这一点。
- MR. KRABS, NO!
- 先生。蟹蟹，不！
DON'T DO IT!
不要这样做！
[grunts]
[rip]
[咕哝]
[撕裂]
- OOH! OH...
[thump]
- 哦！哦...
[扑通]
- OH!
[thump]
- 哦！
[扑通]
- OH, CALM DOWN!
- 哦，冷静点！
IT'S JUST PLANKTON.
这只是浮游生物。
[pop]
[流行音乐]
- SEE?
- UH...GOO-GOO?
- 看？
- 呃...咕咕？
- HOW DARE YOU!
- 你怎么敢！
YOU TOYED WITH OUR EMOTIONS!
你玩弄了我们的感情！
[squish]
- OW.
[挤压]
-哦。
- FACE IT, PLANKTON.
- 面对现实吧，浮游生物。
YOU'RE NEVER GONNA WIN.
你永远不会赢。
I'LL ALWAYS BE
ONE STEP...AHEAD.
我将永远是
领先一步...
[chuckles]
[笑声]
NOW, WHY DON'T YOU GO BACK
TO WHERE YOU CAME FROM,
现在，你为什么不回去
到你来自哪里，
YOU LITTLE BRAT.
你这个小家伙。
[whoosh, crash]
[嗖嗖，崩溃]
all: [gasp]
全体：[喘气]
- UH-OH.
- 呃-哦。
- YOU MONSTER!
- HOW DARE YOU!
- 你这个怪物！
- 你怎么敢！
- [wailing]
- [哀号]
- AWW, DIDDUMS FAIL
TO GET A KRABBY PATTY AGAIN?
- 哇哦，迪达姆失败了
想要再吃一份蟹肉饼吗？
[horn honks]
[喇叭鸣响]
- STOP PATRONIZING ME!
- 别再光顾我了！
WHY DOES EVERY SINGLE PLAN
FALL APART?
为什么每一个计划
分崩离析？
IT'S JUST A STUPID SANDWICH!
这只是一个愚蠢的三明治！
I TELL YOU,
IT'S WEARING ME DOWN!
我告诉你，
这让我精疲力竭！
- YOU NEED
TO STOP OBSESSING OVER IT.
- 你需要
停止沉迷于此。
RELAX. GET A HOBBY
OR SOMETHING.
放松。培养一个爱好
或者什么。
- I HATE TO ADMIT IT,
COMPUTER WIFE,
- 我不愿意承认这一点
电脑妻子，
BUT YOU'RE PROBABLY RIGHT.
但你可能是对的。
I NEED SOMETHING
我需要一些东西
TO TAKE MY MIND OFF
THAT BLASTED SECRET FORMULA
让我放下心来
那个该死的秘密配方
FOR A WHILE.
一阵子。
BUT WHAT?
- I KNOW.
但是什么？
- 我知道。
HOW ABOUT TAKING CARE
OF AN INFERIOR LIFE-FORM?
如何照顾
低等生命形式？
- YOU MEAN A PET?
- 你是说宠物吗？
THAT'S A GREAT IDEA!
这是个好主意！
BUT HOW WILL I FIND A PET
但我怎样才能找到宠物
THAT FITS
MY DYNAMIC PERSONALITY?
适合
我的个性充满活力？
- PLANKTON.
- [screams]
- 浮游生物。
- [尖叫]
- I HAVE THE PERFECT SOLUTION
TO YOUR PROBLEM.
- 我有完美的解决方案
针对您的问题。
- SPONGEBOB?
- 海绵宝宝？
HOW COULD YOU
POSSIBLY HELP ME?
你怎么可以
可以帮助我吗？
- YOU SHOULD TRY
THE LOCAL ANIMAL SHELTER.
- 你应该尝试
当地的动物收容所。
THAT'S WHERE I FOUND
MY GARY.
这就是我发现的地方
我的加里。
- OH, YEAH?
- 哦，是吗？
PERHAPS YOU'RE
ON TO SOMETHING THERE.
也许你是
去那里做某事。
- HERE IT IS.
- 这里是。
THE BIKINI BOTTOM
ANIMAL SHELTER.
比基尼泳裤
动物收容所。
[pets barking]
YOUR PERFECT PET AWAITS.
[宠物吠叫]
您的完美宠物正在等待着您。
NOW, IF YOU JUST LISTEN
TO YOUR HEART,
现在，只要你听着
致你的心，
YOU'LL BE ABLE
TO PICK OUT THE RIGHT PET
你一定能够
选择合适的宠物
AS SOON AS YOU SEE IT.
一看到它。
[barking continues]
- HMM. TOO BIG.
[吠叫继续]
- 嗯。太大了。
TOO SLOPPY.
太马虎了。
- DUH.
- TOO STUPID.
- 呃。
- 太愚蠢了。
- HI, SPONGEBOB.
- 嗨，海绵宝宝。
- HEY, PATRICK.
- 嘿，帕特里克。
OH! OH!
WHAT ABOUT THIS ONE?
哦！哦！
这个怎么样？
- ARE YOU KIDDING ME?
- 你在开玩笑吧？
ALGAE ON A ROCK?
岩石上的藻类？
I WANT A PET,
NOT A PLANT.
我想要一只宠物，
不是植物。
IT'S NO USE.
这没有用。
- [snarls]
- [咆哮]
- THERE'S NOTHING FOR ME HERE.
- 这里没有什么适合我的。
[screams]
[尖叫声]
- OH, NO!
PLANKTON!
- 哦，不！
浮游生物！
- YOU KNOW,
I CAN'T SAY I'M SURPRISED.
- 你知道，
我不能说我很惊讶。
- [barking]
- [吠叫]
[growls, chomps]
[咆哮，咀嚼]
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
- [barks]
- [吠叫]
- HEY THERE, LITTLE GUY.
- 嘿，小家伙。
- [barks]
- LOOKS LIKE WE HAVE A WINNER.
- [吠叫]
- 看起来我们有一个赢家。
- OH, SO CUTE!
- 哦，太可爱了！
WHATCHA GONNA CALL HIM?
该怎么称呼他？
HE LOOKS LIKE A "SPOT" TO ME.
他对我来说就像一个“点”。
- [chomps, growling]
- [咀嚼，咆哮]
- THAT NAME PROVOKES
A VIOLENT REACTION.
- 这个名字激怒了
激烈的反应。
SPOT IT IS!
发现它了！
- [barks, panting]
- [吠叫，气喘吁吁]
- WELL, SPOT.
- 好吧，点。
I'M YOUR NEW OWNER,
我是你的新主人，
SO SHOWER ME
WITH LOVE AND AFFECTION.
所以给我洗澡吧
充满爱和感情。
KAREN,
凯伦，
IT'S NOT GIVING ME
UNCONDITIONAL LOVE.
它没有给我
无条件的爱。
I THINK IT'S DEFECTIVE.
我认为它有缺陷。
- YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
TO TRAIN HIM TO DO THAT.
- 你将会有
训练他这样做。
- I TRAIN HIM?
- 我训练他？
[sighs]
I'LL GIVE IT A SHOT.
[叹气]
我会尝试一下。
ALL RIGHT, SPOT.
好吧，点。
LET'S START
WITH SOMETHING EASY.
让我们开始吧
简单的事情。
STAY.
停留。
GOOD BOY.
NOW SIT.
好孩子。
现在坐下。
[squishing]
[压扁]
VERY GOOD!
非常好！
NOW ROLL OVER.
现在翻身。
- [barks]
- EXCELLENT!
- [吠叫]
- 太棒了！
NOW SHAKE.
现在摇一摇。
[rumbling, clattering]
[隆隆声，咔哒声]
WOW!
哇！
THAT'S ONE MEAN SHAKE
YOU GOT THERE.
这是一次剧烈的震动
你到了。
I THINK WE SHOULD BURN OFF
SOME OF THAT EXTRA ENERGY.
我认为我们应该燃烧掉
一些额外的能量。
WOULD YOU LIKE
TO GO WALKIES?
你愿意吗
去散步吗？
I'LL ASSUME THAT'S A YES.
我假设这是肯定的。
MARCH!
行进！
- [barking]
- [吠叫]
- [whistles cheerfully]
- [愉快地吹口哨]
[whistling peters out]
[口哨声逐渐消失]
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
PHEW!
唷！
WE MUST'VE WALKED FOR MILES.
我们一定已经走了好几英里了。
[squishes]
[压扁]
I GUESS OUR LEGS
ARE TOO SHORT FOR WALKIES.
我猜我们的腿
对于步行来说太短了。
HOW ABOUT
A NICE ROUND OF FETCH?
怎么样
一轮漂亮的取球？
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
FETCH!
拿来！
[splat]
[啪嗒]
[snap]
[折断]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
OH, NO.
哦，不。
WHAT HAVE I DONE?
我做了什么？
I'M A TERRIBLE PET OWNER!
TERRIBLE!
我是一个糟糕的宠物主人！
糟糕的！
KAREN!
凯伦！
WE'RE GONNA NEED ANOTHER SPOT!
我们需要另一个地方！
[squishing]
[压扁]
- [barks]
- [吠叫]
- NICE REBOUND, SPOT!
- 反弹不错，点！
YOU KNOW,
I GET SQUISHED A LOT TOO.
你知道，
我也经常被压扁。
[sniffles]
[抽鼻子]
I HOPE NOBODY SAW
THAT EMOTIONAL OUTBURST.
我希望没有人看到
那种情绪的爆发。
all: AW.
全体：AW。
- SHOO!
- 嘘！
OKAY, SPOT.
好的，点。
TODAY, YOU'LL LEARN
HOW TO BE AN ATTACK PET
今天，您将学到
如何成为攻击宠物
TO GUARD THE CHUM BUCKET
FROM INTRUDERS.
保护鱼缸
来自入侵者。
NOW, SPOT,
PRETEND I'M A BURGLAR.
现在，现货，
假装我是一个窃贼。
ATTACK!
攻击！
- [whimpers]
- [呜咽]
- YOU'RE NOT GETTING THIS?
- 你不明白吗？
COME AT ME!
来找我吧！
UH-OH,
LOSING BALANCE.
呃-哦，
失去平衡。
A LITTLE HELP?
有一点帮助吗？
- [boings]
- [嘘声]
[barks]
[吠叫]
- ON SECOND THOUGHT,
- 再想一想，
WHAT DO I NEED
A GUARD DOG FOR?
我需要什么
看门狗的用途？
I CAN'T EVEN GIVE CHUM AWAY.
我什至不能放弃密友。
WHAT I REALLY NEED
IS A RETRIEVER.
我真正需要什么
是一只猎犬。
THIS IS YOUR TARGET.
这是你的目标。
I WANT YOU TO RETRIEVE
THE KRABBY PATTY.
我要你找回
蟹肉饼。
NOW, SECURITY IS TIGHT,
现在，安全很严格，
SO I'VE DEVISED A PL--
所以我设计了一个 PL--
WAIT!
等待！
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
你要去哪里？
YOU'RE NOT READY!
你还没准备好！
- [sniffing]
- [嗅嗅]
[pop]
[流行音乐]
[sniffing]
[嗅嗅]
- [humming cheerfully]
- [欢快地哼唱]
- I'D LIKE A LARGE...
- 我想要一个大的...
WHAT WAS THAT?
那是什么？
- DIDN'T SEE IT,
DON'T CARE.
- 没看到，
不在乎。
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
[thump]
- [barking]
[扑通]
- [吠叫]
- HOLY PLOT TWIST!
- 神圣的情节转折！
IT'S A KRABBY PATTY!
这是蟹肉饼！
IT'S...A MIRACLE!
[heavenly choir vocals]
这……真是一个奇迹！
【天籁合唱团的歌声】
KAREN, LOOK
AT WHAT SPOT BROUGHT HOME.
凯伦，看
在什么地方带回家。
- THAT'S WONDERFUL!
- 太棒了！
SPOT DESERVES A REWARD.
SPOT 值得奖励。
- HE CAN HAVE
ANYTHING HE WANTS,
- 他可以拥有
他想要什么，
UP TO HALF MY KINGDOM--
我的王国的一半——
UH, LABORATORY.
呃，实验室。
- I THINK HE WANTS
YOUR KRABBY PATTY.
- 我想他想要
你的蟹肉饼。
- [panting]
- [气喘吁吁]
[chomps]
- NOO!
[咀嚼]
- 不！
NO!
不！
YOU'VE BEEN A VERY BAD AMOEBA!
你是一只非常糟糕的阿米巴原虫！
BAD AMOEBA!
坏阿米巴！
I'M AFRAID YOU'LL HAVE
TO BE PUNISHED.
我担心你会有
受到惩罚。
YOU NEED A TIME OUT.
你需要暂停一下。
I'M JUST GONNA TIE YOU UP
OUT HERE
我只是要把你绑起来
在这里
UNTIL YOU LEARN
TO BEHAVE.
直到你学会为止
行为规范。
SHOULDN'T TAKE
MORE THAN FIVE MINUTES.
不应该采取
超过五分钟。
- [whimpers, yaps]
- [呜咽，嘶哑]
- AW...
- 艾维...
NO, NO,
I MUST BE STRONG.
不，不，
我必须坚强。
- [whimpers]
- [呜咽]
- I CAN'T DO IT.
- 我做不到。
[tender music]
SPOT, I'M SORRY. I--
[温柔的音乐]
现货，对不起。我 -
[music peters out]
[音乐逐渐消失]
[tense music]
[紧张的音乐]
SPOT!
点！
HE'S GONE.
他走了。
[crying]
WHERE IS HE?
[哭泣]
他在哪里？
SPOT! COME BACK!
点！回来！
[sobbing] SPOT!
COME BACK!
[抽泣]现货！
回来！
I'VE GOT TO FIND HIM.
我必须找到他。
all: AW.
全体：AW。
- DON'T ANY OF YOU HAVE JOBS?
- 你们都没有工作吗？
SPOT!
点！
WHERE ARE YOU, SPOT!
你在哪里，现货！
[sobbing]
[抽泣]
- WHY, PLANKTON,
WHAT'S WRONG?
- 为什么，浮游生物，
怎么了？
- I LOST SPOT.
- 我失去了位置。
- THAT'S TERRIBLE!
- 太糟糕了！
GARY LOST ME ONCE.
加里曾经失去过我一次。
I WAS COLD, ALONE, STARVING.
我很冷，孤独，饥饿。
IT WAS THE WORST EIGHT MINUTES
OF MY LIFE.
这是最糟糕的八分钟
我的生活。
COME ON, PLANKTON,
LET'S FIND YOUR PET.
来吧，浮游生物，
让我们找到您的宠物。
LOST PET!
丢失宠物！
ANYONE SEEN THIS LOST PET?
有人看到这只丢失的宠物吗？
LOST PET EMERGENCY!
丢失宠物紧急情况！
BE ON THE LOOKOUT
FOR A LOST PET!
保持警惕
为了丢失的宠物！
PARDON ME, SIR.
HAVE YOU SEEN THIS AMOEBA?
请原谅我，先生。
你见过这种阿米巴原虫吗？
- YOU MEAN THAT LITTLE SPECK?
- NO.
- 你是说那个小斑点吗？
- 不。
THAT LITTLE SPECK.
- IS THIS HIM?
那个小斑点。
- 这是他吗？
- NO, THAT'S A PIECE OF GUM.
- 不，那是一块口香糖。
- GUM?
- 古姆？
I'VE BEEN LOOKING EVERYWHERE
FOR THIS.
我一直在到处寻找
为此。
IF I WAS LOOKIN'
FOR A LOST PET,
如果我在看
对于丢失的宠物，
I'D TRY THE ANIMAL SHELTER.
我会尝试动物收容所。
- OF COURSE!
- 当然！
both: THE SHELTER!
两者：庇护所！
- I THINK IT'S CLOSED
FOR THE NIGHT.
- 我想它已经关门了
为了夜晚。
[door clanks]
[门叮当作响]
OOH, IT'S DARK IN HERE.
哦，这里很黑。
I'LL FIND A LIGHT SWITCH.
我会找到一个电灯开关。
AHA!
[switch clicks]
啊哈！
[切换点击]
[metallic clank]
NO, THAT'S NOT IT.
[金属叮当声]
不，不是这样。
[switch clicks]
[切换点击]
AHA! FOUND THE LIGHTS.
啊哈！找到灯了。
- UH, SPONGEBOB?
- 呃，海绵宝宝？
WHAT WAS THAT FIRST SWITCH FOR?
第一个开关的用途是什么？
- I DUNNO.
- 我不知道。
I THINK IT UNLOCKS THE PENS?
我认为它可以解锁笔？
- I THOUGHT SO.
- 我是这么想的。
BECAUSE NOW
THE ANIMALS ARE LOOSE!
因为现在
动物们都松了！
[animals shriek]
[动物尖叫]
- SPONGEBOB?
- RUN FOR IT?
- 海绵宝宝？
- 为之奔跑？
- YEP.
- 是的。
- [panting]
- [气喘吁吁]
[animals shrieking]
[动物尖叫]
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
I THINK WE LOST 'EM.
我想我们失去了他们。
- SPONGEBOB,
BEFORE WE'RE TORN TO SHREDS,
- 海绵宝宝，
在我们被撕成碎片之前，
I'D LIKE TO THANK YOU
FOR HELPING ME LOOK FOR SPOT.
我想谢谢你
帮助我寻找地点。
- AW, IT WAS NOTHING.
- 噢，没什么。
HEY, SPEAKING OF SPOTS.
嘿，说到斑点。
DID YOU ALWAYS HAVE
A DOUBLE PUPIL?
你一直有吗
双瞳？
- A DOUBLE WHAT?
- 双什么？
[snap]
[折断]
[pop]
SPOT!
[流行音乐]
现货！
[dramatic music]
THANK ENTROPY YOU'RE SAFE!
[戏剧音乐]
感谢熵，你安全了！
YOU WERE HIDING
ON MY OPTICAL CORNEA
你躲起来了
在我的视角膜上
THE WHOLE TIME!
一直以来！
YOU SNEAKY LITTLE AMOEBA, YOU.
你这个狡猾的小变形虫，你。
- [barks]
- [吠叫]
- [laughs]
- [笑]
- AW, I'M GLAD
YOU FOUND SPOT.
- 噢，我很高兴
您找到了位置。
[animals shrieking]
[动物尖叫]
UNFORTUNATELY,
THE ANIMALS FOUND US TOO.
不幸的是，
动物也找到了我们。
- GOOD-BYE, SPOT.
- 再见，斯波特。
I GUESS THIS IS THE END
OF THE ROAD FOR US.
我想这就是结局
我们的道路。
- [growls]
- [咆哮]
[barks]
[吠叫]
- SPOT, NO!
- 现货，不！
- [barking]
- [吠叫]
[laughter]
[笑声]
[snarling]
[咆哮]
[barking]
[叫声]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
*
[growls, barks]
[咆哮，吠叫]
- WOW, SPOT!
YOU SAVED US!
- 哇，现货！
你救了我们！
- I TAUGHT HIM
EVERYTHING HE KNOWS!
- 我教他
他知道的一切！
- [barks]
- [吠叫]
[lilting ukulele music]
[轻快的尤克里里音乐]
**